A Finding Aid to the Linda Nochlin Papers, circa 1876, 1937-2017, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1946-2014; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Boxes 5-7, OV 35; 0.058 Gigabytes ER005-ER011, ER120
  - Family, Regarding Student Travel to United Kingdom, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Family, Responses to Invitations to Nochlin's Mother's Birthday Party, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Fan Mail from Peers, 1972-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fan Mail for "Why Have There Been No Great Women Artists?", 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - First Names Only, 1959-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - First Names Only, Digital Files, 1991-2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER007)
  - Friedberg, Rachel, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fryd, Vivien Green, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - G, 1990-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Gagosian Gallery, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Getty Research Institute, 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Granet, Rosaline, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Guggenheim Museum, 1988; 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - H, 1986-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Harris, Ann Sutherland, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Harvard University, 2002-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
    File contains material regarding Nochlin's appointment as the Charles Eliot Norton Professor of Poetry.
  - Haye, Jonathan, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Hayum, Andrée, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Heller, Richard, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Herding, Klaus, 1988; 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Heresies Magazine, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Honig, Elizabeth Alice, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - I-J, 1988-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Jaffe, Shirley, circa 1975-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Jarrasse, Dominique, Regarding, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Jewishness and Visual Art, Regarding, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - J. Paul Getty Museum, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - K, 1989-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Katz, Paul, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 33)
    Includes illustrated letters.
  - Kesslers, Marni, 1992; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER008)
  - Krauss, Rosalind, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Kronsky, Betty J., 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Kyoto Institute of Technology, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - L, 1989-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Lajer-Burcharth, Ewa, 1989-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Lehr, Mira, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Letter to the Editor, Regarding Young Spartans Exercising by Degas, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Letters by Nochlin to Senators Regarding Federal Budget Cuts, Drafts, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Levin, Robert, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - M, 1986-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Manet's Portrait of Henri Rochefort, Regarding, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Mangold, Sylvia, Regarding, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Melot, Michel, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1993-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Mitchell, Joan, circa 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 48)
    Includes a copy of Nochlin's letter to Mitchell.
  - Mitelberg, Zuka, circa 1975-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 49)
    Includes photographs of Nochlin and Mitelberg.
  - Monahan, Laurie, Regarding Dissertation on André Masson, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Mundy, James, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER009)
  - Musée du Louvre, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Musée d'Orsay, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Museum of Modern Art, Regarding the Elizabeth Murray Panel, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - N, 1988-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - National Gallery of Canada, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - National Portrait Gallery, Australia, 1999-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - New York University, Grey Art Gallery, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - New York University, Regarding Nochlin's Participation in Programs, 1997-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - O, 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Ockman, Carol, 1971-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - P, 1986-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Pearlstein, Philip, 1966-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Penguin Books Ltd, 1971-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1990-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Piper, Adrian, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Postcards to Nochlin, 1971-circa 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Princeton University, 1989-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Publisher Letters with Nochlin's Responses, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - R, 1980-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Randall, Francis B., circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Reilly, Maura, 1992; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER010)
  - Rosenblum, Naomi, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Rosenblum, Robert, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Rosenthal, Nan, Regarding, 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 73)
    Folder contains a photocopy of Nochlin's sympathy letter to Henry Benning Cortesi after Rosenthal's death.
  - Roth, Moira, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - S, 1971-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - S, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 35)
  - Schaffner, Ingrid, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Schapiro, Miriam, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Schneemann, Carolee, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Sennett, Richard, 1993; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 1 computer file (Folder ER011)
  - Shannon, Joe, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Sleigh, Sylvia, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Spector, Jack, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Steele, Elizabeth, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Stimpson, Catharine, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - St. Louis Vassar Club, 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - St. Louis Vassar Club, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 35)
  - T, 1992-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Thames and Hudson Ltd, 1986-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Tillim, Sidney, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tucker, Anand, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified or Illegible, 1963-circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago Book Order, Regarding, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - University of Rochester, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - V, 1982-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Vassi, Marco, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Voss, Julia, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - W, 1988-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Washington University in St. Louis, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Weinberg, Jonathan, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Weiner, Malcolm, Regarding, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Whitney Museum of Art, 1988-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Writings About Andy Warhol, Regarding, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Z, 1990-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Writing Project Files, circa 1876; 1953-2016; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 17 Linear feet Boxes 7-21, 30-31, 33-34, OVs 36-37; 3.72 Gigabytes ER012-ER102
  The files in this series document Nochlin's prolific writing career. The series includes her lifelong research and work on Gustave Courbet, realism, bathers and the body, as well as numerous essays and lectures, research and writings on artists, and other types of writing projects. In addition to draft writings and typescripts, the folders include documents and digital material related to the projects such as correspondence, contracts, lecture material, outlines, four sound recordings, and research material that may contain photographic materials, photocopies of images and articles, notes, bibliographies, travel documents, and student and colleague papers.
  The series is divided into six subseries.
  4.1: Files on Gustave Courbet and Realism, 1959-2010
  4.2: Files on Bathers and the Body, 1980-2005
  4.3: Essays, 1953-2012
  4.4: Lectures, 1956-2014
  4.5: Files on Artists, 1968-2016
  4.6: Other Writing Projects, 1953-2016
  The subseries are arranged alphabetically, then chronologically within the folders.
  - Files on Gustave Courbet and Realism, circa 1876; 1959-2010; 4.1; Archival Resource Key
    Included in this subseries are drafts and notes for Nochlin's dissertation, "Gustave Courbet: A Study of Style and Society," published in 1976 which was the genesis of Nochlin's lifelong study of Courbet and his relation to realism. The subseries includes drafts, correspondence, lectures, outlines, typescripts, contracts, and research material that includes an original letter written by Courbet, circa 1876. Additional material on Courbet can be found within the teaching files in series 6, subseries 6.1.
    - "American New Realism," Notes for Morocco Conference, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Annotated Books on Courbet, 1959-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence and Articles on Courbet by Klaus Herding, 1977-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence and Articles on Courbet by Klaus Herding, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 36)
    - Correspondence Regarding "The Burial at Ornans": Courbet's Realist Manifesto" by Claudette Mainzer, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence Regarding Courbet, 1962-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence and Manuscripts by Others About Realism, 1976-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Courbet Exhibition at Grand Palais, Annotated Exhibition Catalog, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Courbet Exhibition at Grand Palais, Notes, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Courbet and 19th Century Realism, Lecture in Dallas, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - "Courbet's Beggar Woman" Lectures and Exhibition Materials, 2009-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - "Courbet's Burial at Ornans" Draft for Portfolio Magazine, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - "Courbet, the Commune, and the Visual Arts" Drafts, 1978-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 29)
      Includes one notebook.
    - "Courbet, the Commune, and the Visual Arts," Research, 1909; 1950-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - "Courbet, David and the Imaginary Afterlife of the Revolution" Lectures, 1989-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Courbet und Deutschland Catalog Translations by Peter Chametzky, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Courbet und Deutschland Catalog Translations by Peter Chametzky, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - "Courbet and the Heritage of Realism" Lecture at Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - "Courbet and His Century: A Study of Ideas and Style," Contracts and Outlines, circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - "Courbet and His Century: A Study of Ideas and Style," Notes, circa 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - "Courbet and His Century: A Study of Ideas and Style," Notes, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - "Courbet and His Century: A Study of Ideas and Style," Notes, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 38)
      Includes one notecard book.
    - "Courbet and His Territory: How Landscape Means" Lecture, (1 of 2), 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "Courbet and His Territory: How Landscape Means" Lecture, (2 of 2), 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Courbet and the Japanese Print, Research Material, 1967-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "Courbet, Millet, Daumier and the Image of the Working Woman in the Later 19th Century," Drafts, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "Courbet, Millet, Daumier and the Image of the Working Woman in the Later 19th Century," Lecture at Courbet Colloquium in Frankfurt, Germany, 1978-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Courbet, Millet, Daumier and the Image of the Working Woman in the Later 19th Century," Lecture at Courbet Colloquium in Frankfurt, Germany, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - "Courbet, Millet, Daumier and the Image of the Working Woman in the Later 19th Century," Lecture Notes, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Courbet à Neuf! Colloquium at Musée d'Orsay, Program Material, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "Courbet's Oak of Flagey," Drafts, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "Courbet's Oak of Flagey," Drafts, circa 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "Courbet's Oak of Flagey," Drafts, circa 1983-circa 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - "Courbet's Oak of Flagey," Drafts with Notes, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - "Courbet's Oak of Flagey," Notebook, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - "Courbet's Oak of Flagey," Notebook, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "Courbet's Oak of Flagey," Notebook, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "Courbet's Oak of Flagey," Working Copy, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "Courbet, Oller, and a Sense of Place," Drafts and Research, 1967-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Courbet's L'Origine du Monde: The Origin Without an Original," Drafts, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "Courbet's L'Origine du Monde: The Origin Without an Original," Research, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "Courbet's Real Allegory: Rereading The Painter's Studio," Digital Drafts, 1995; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 2 computer files (Folder ER012)
    - "Courbet's Real Allegory: Rereading The Painter's Studio," Final Drafts and Illustrations, 2006-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - "Courbet's Real Allegory: Rereading The Painter's Studio," Notes, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "Courbet's Real Allegory: Rereading The Painter's Studio," Note Card Book, circa 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "Courbet's Real Allegory: Rereading The Painter's Studio," Notes on "The Erotic", 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "Courbet's Real Allegory: Rereading The Painter's Studio," Notes on Writings by Klaus Herding, circa 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - "Courbet's Real Allegory: Rereading The Painter's Studio," Outlines, 1984-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - "Courbet's Real Allegory: Rereading The Painter's Studio," Related Papers, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - "Courbet's Real Allegory: Rereading The Painter's Studio," Typescripts, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Courbet's Real Allegory: Rereading The Painter's Studio," Typescripts, 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Courbet: A Reappraisal," Conference Session Presentations and Notes, 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Courbet Reconsidered, Bibliography, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Courbet Reconsidered, Catalog Entries 1A-11A, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Courbet Reconsidered, Catalog Entries 1-20, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Courbet Reconsidered, Catalog Entries 21-45, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Courbet Reconsidered, Catalog Entries 46-64, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Courbet Reconsidered, Catalog Entries 65-88, circa 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Courbet Reconsidered, Correspondence, 1986-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Courbet Reconsidered, Essays with Artwork Location Lists, circa 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Courbet Reconsidered, Exhibition Loans, 1984-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Courbet Reconsidered, Notes, 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Courbet Reconsidered, Printed Material, 1988-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - "Courbet's Sleep: The Nude as Problematic in Nineteenth Century Painting," Lecture at Emory University, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - "The De-Politicization of Gustave Courbet: Transformation and Rehabilitation Under the Third Republic," Lecture at CAA Conference in New York, 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Dissertation, Drafts, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Dissertation, Drafts and Outline (1 of 3), 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Dissertation, Drafts and Outline (2 of 3), 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Dissertation, Drafts and Outline - Material from Box 9, Folder 1, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Dissertation, Drafts and Outline (3 of 3), 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Dissertation, Drafts and Outline - Material from Box 9, Folder 22, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Dissertation, Notes, circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Essays on Courbet by Others, 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Essays on Courbet by Others, 1987-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - "The Flowering of American Realism" Essay, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - "Gustave Courbet's Meeting: A Portrait of the Artist as a Wandering Jew," Notes (1 of 2), 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Gustave Courbet's Meeting: A Portrait of the Artist as a Wandering Jew," Notes (2 of 2), 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Images of Artwork, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Images of Artwork, 1971-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Images of Artwork, Felix Trutat, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Images of Artwork, Negatives, circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "Living with Courbet: Fifty Years of My Life as an Art Historian," Lectures, 1989-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "Living with Courbet: Fifty Years of My Life as an Art Historian," Lectures, 2007-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - "The New Realists" for Realism Now Exhibition Catalog, Drafts and Correspondence, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - "The New Realists" for Realism Now Exhibition Catalog, Research, 1967-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "The New Realists" for Realism Now Exhibition Catalog, Research, 1967-1976; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 36)
    - Notecards, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 30)
      See sets 1-6
    - Notecards - Material Removed from Box 30, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Notecards, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 31)
    - Notecards - Material Removed from Box 31, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "Oak as Heroism of Modern Life," Draft and Notes, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Poem/Free Form Notes on Courbet, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Photographs of Courbet's Sketchbook, circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Photographs of Musée Courbet, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Portland Art Museum Collection of French Paintings, List, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Presentations on Courbet by Others, 2009; Archival Resource Key; 0.163 Gigabytes 4 computer files (Folder ER013)
    - Real, Really Real, Super Real: Directions in Contemporary American Realism Exhibition, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Realism, Correspondence, 1971-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Realism, Discussant Response at CAA Conference, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Realism, Press, 1964-circa 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Realism, Student Reviews, 1972-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - "Realism Now - and Then," Drafts and Notes, 2001-2004; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 4 computer files (Folder ER014)
    - "Realism Now - and Then," Lecture at New York University, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - "Realism Now - and Then," Lecture at Tate, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "Realism Now - and Then," Lecture at Tate in Glasgow, 2002-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - "Realism in Visual Arts in the 19th Century," Lecture in Netherlands, 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - The Realist Tradition: French Painting and Drawing 1830-1900 Exhibition Catalog, Correspondence, 1979-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - The Realist Tradition: French Painting and Drawing 1830-1900 Exhibition Catalog, Drafts and Research, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Research, Courbet and the Police, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Research, Courbet and the Police, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Research, Courbet and the Police, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Research, General, circa 1970-circa 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Research, General, circa 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Research, Invoices and Receipts for Photograph Reproductions, 1962-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Research, Letter and Writings by Courbet, circa 1876; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Research, Paris Commune, 1972-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Research, Related Cartoons, circa 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Research, The Sleeping Spinner, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Carton 5)
    - Research Trip to Europe, Itinerary and Artwork Lists, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Some Thoughts on Realism," Draft, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 7)